Previously on Bates Motel...
I never seen anyone go
into a hole like that.
Did anyone call my mother?
[Scoffs] No, they just called me.
Well, please don't tell her.
That girl is not a good choice.
She's rude. She's disrespectful to adults.
She's a nice girl.
Don't you walk out on me
when I'm talking to you!
Hey, get back here now!
- [Crying]
- You okay?
I told you to wait in the car.
My dad's a dick. Whatever.
[Gunshots]
[Tires screech]
I heard you just saved my brother's life.
- Who are you?
- I'm your boss.
Morning, mother. What's for breakfast?
I didn't make anything. I
actually have to go into town.
I have to do some errands.
Oh, you want me to come?
We can get breakfast out.
No, I have stuff to do.
Stay here and help Emma.
[Metal clinks]
When were you drinking? Was this with Cody?
Don't make a big deal of it.
You know, all kids my age drink.
I didn't raise you to be
all your kids your age.
I raised you to be better.
We're supposed to be taking you to get
your driver's license test this weekend.
How am I supposed to feel okay
about letting you have that,
when you're doing stuff like this?
Mom, I need to be able to drive.
Please, I'm a grown man.
Making immature choices.
It's really important to me.
I know it means a lot to you.
I'm sorry about the beer.
I'm trusting you, Norman.
You cannot keep secrets from me.
I'm gonna get dressed.
Put your clothes away.
Someone's supposed to be
picking me up from work.
You're not Remo.
[Laughs]
I hope not.
Come on. Let's go.
Why was I in a hospital two towns over?
Because no one knows
you were in the shootout.
That's why we took you to the
hospital over in ocean view.
It's a better hospital also.
So I wanted to make sure you had the best,
given you jumped in front of a car
to save my dumb-ass brother.
♪ We are so very sorry ♪
You live up here?
♪ There is little we can do ♪
No, I'm taking you up here to kill you.
[Laughs] Yeah, I live up here.
♪ She didn't beg, oh, not enough ♪
It's a hell of a commute.
Well, let's just say I don't love visitors.
♪ She wasn't there
when things got bad ♪
♪ I never ever saw
the northern lights ♪
[Dogs bark]
Dozer! Dozer!
Oh, it's okay. It's okay, honey, yeah.
Come on, I'll show you inside.
Don't let the goat bite you in the ass.
[Goat bleats]
Come here. [Whistles]
Come on, come on. Come on, come on.
So, uh, your room's upstairs.
You'll be safe here
until this all blows over.
Are you sure you're not gonna kill me?
[Laughs] Opposite, actually.
I'm very interested in keeping you alive.
Do you have family?
Anyone I need to call,
so they're not worried about you?
No, they don't care about me.
That came out way more pathetic
than it was supposed to.
But, uh, it's fine I'm here.
Here you go.
- [Tapping keys]
- Yes?
Hi, it's Norma Bates.
I need to see Nick Ford.
Hello, Mrs. Bates.
I don't show that Mr. Ford
has an appointment with you.
Well, he doesn't.
I'm sorry. I don't have him right now.
Well, okay, I'll just drive home,
call him, and then come back.
Okay, Mrs. Bates.
- Norma?
- Oh, hi.
I was just trying to get
in to see you for a moment.
I wanted to talk to you.
I guess you heard the news.
Well, if you mean about Lee Berman,
yes, it's so sad.
Mm, sad... And convenient.
Well, I would never say
someone dying is convenient.
Well, then you'd be lying or ignorant.
There are many times, Norma,
when death is convenient.
I don't want to do this anymore.
You don't want to do what? Stop the bypass?
Well, no. I still want that.
But I-I don't want to do this.
You and me, this.
It's nothing personal.
I just... this is very important to me,
and we barely know each other.
That didn't seem to
bother you the other day.
Before you had the
environmental impact report.
Before Lee Berman drove off a cliff.
Well, I just think it's strange,
Lee Berman dying all of a sudden.
What are you saying,
I had something to do
with Lee Berman's death?
No, I'm not saying that at all.
That would be crazy, right?
I just feel that I can take it from here.
Well, it's... it's been
great getting to meet you,
and I wish you all the best.
You be well, Norma Bates.
[Gate opens, closes]
[Crackling electricity]
Hi.
I had to come over.
Isn't that the weirdest
news about Lee Berman?
- I couldn't believe it.
- I know.
It's terribly sad. He had a wife and kids.
You know, you need to try
and get that open seat.
Does that seem right?
He's dead, the seat's open,
and that bypass is still happening.
I'm not saying it's gonna be easy.
There's gonna be a line
of people trying for it.
But a lot of the people around
here in this town are yokels.
And I know Rob is trying
to get a council together
that's a little bit more
sophisticated and educated.
Not... not to sound like a snob.
I seriously don't mean it that way.
But people a little more like... like us.
- Who's Rob?
- The mayor of our city.
Oh, Rob, yeah. Right.
I just... He doesn't even know me.
Well, call him, and tell him
that you want to talk to him
about taking over the seat.
Tell him you're a friend
of mine and Peter's.
They play golf together.
And I'm gonna have George call you
to help prep you for the meeting.
No, I'm not trying to set you up again.
I can take a hint.
I mean, it's not him. He's wonderful.
- I'm just not ready yet.
- Please.
It's just he's fantastic
at this kind of thing.
He was a lawyer for many years.
Politics have always been a hobby of his.
He helped three senators get elected,
and I really think he
could help get this seat.
Really?
I don't want to put you to trouble.
Norma, stop it.
It's no trouble at all.
I am gonna call him.
I think it would be great
to have a smart, single mom
with a business on the board.
Let me know how that call goes, okay?
[Dogs barking]
[Door opens]
You slept a long time.
That's good.
What's this?
It's a little elixir I made for you
from some herbs in my garden.
Lavender is the main component.
It has anti-inflammatory
and antiseptic properties.
It also aids in insomnia and anxiety...
Depression.
But that's not our problem.
Go ahead. Drink it.
So I'm gonna make dinner for us.
We'll eat around 7:00.
- Okay, yeah.
- Okay.
Thank you.
I mean, for...
You know, bringing me to your own home.
[Door closes]
I'm just dropping off some towels.
Maybe I need more towels.
- I'll bring some later.
- [Laughs] I'll be here.
I thought you had to go sell pot.
I can work around your schedule.
[Laughs] I'll see what I can do.
Do you want to go for a drive later?
Sounds good.
- Okay.
- I'll make it work.
But I've... I've really
got to go deliver towels.
Okay, okay, enjoy your towels.
[Laughs]
Oh, I will.
Hey, Emma.
What are you doing?
Oh, nothing.
You know, Cody's just picking me up.
Okay.
[Deap Vally's Bad For My Body]
♪ doing things that
are bad for my body ♪
are bad for my head ♪
♪ doing things that
are bad for my future ♪
♪ 'cause I can't help myself ♪
♪ doing things that
are bad for my body ♪
are bad for my wealth ♪
♪ doing things that
are bad for my credit ♪
Turn that music off, please.
What? I can't hear you.
- [Turns radio off]
- Thank you.
Norman, give me a moment with Cody, please.
I don't want my son drinking with you.
[Laughs] Who said we were drinking?
There's reasons he shouldn't drink,
medical reasons.
That's all I'm gonna say.
So don't encourage him to
do it, do you understand me?
Yeah.
That's the last time you go with her.
I'm not gonna make a scene today,
but I'll drive you from now on.
Mom, you won't have to,
okay? I'll have my license.
Just promise me you'll use your head,
and you're not gonna let that girl
make you do anything stupid.
Mother, I promise.
♪ Well, we all saw this all coming ♪
You okay?
Yeah.
Let's blow off tech.
I don't want to go build crap today.
Let's go to the swimming hole at the river.
Don't we need to show up and do our job?
[Laughs]
You're awesome.
I'm gonna swing by my place
and steal some liquor before we head out.
- You like rum?
- Hmm.
I don't really, but neither does he,
so he won't notice if it's missing.
[Car approaching]
It's my dad. Something happened.
Come on.
[Door opens]
[Door slams]
[Objects clattering]
[Breathing heavily]
Shh.
[Whispers] We're just playing, okay?
We're not going to tell daddy where we are.
- [Thud]
- [Glass breaks]
I know he sounds angry, but
it's just a game, just a game.
I'm not gonna let anybody hurt you.
[Screams]
- [Closet door opens]
- [Gasps]
[Whispers] Norman.
Norman.
[Car door closes]
[Engine turns]
It's okay. Norman, he's gone.
[Opens closet door]
How often is this happening?
I guess more lately.
I don't know why.
What... what happened to your dad?
Uh, I think he just forgot his meds.
His back's screwed up. He left.
You sure you're okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
We can go now.
[Door opens]
Don't you think it's gonna rain?
I don't know. Doesn't really matter.
It's kind of cool to
be outside in the rain.
It's a little cold.
- [Both laugh]
- That's what liquor is for.
I'm sorry about your dad.
What do you mean?
That you're scared of him.
He's not always like that.
Sometimes he's nice.
He's funny when we watch TV together.
[Chuckles softly] He makes a lot of jokes.
I just wish he could be happy.
I'm sorry.
[Chuckles]
Hey, you know what's fun?
What?
[Spits]
[Laughs]
I'm not sure this is a
good day for a picnic.
It'll be fine.
We have each other to keep ourselves warm.
Wish it was warm. I kind
of wanted to go swimming.
How do you do that?
You know, with the... With the O2?
Oh, I just take it out.
I mean, I can't do anything uber-athletic,
but it's workable.
Okay, cool.
Kind of looks like some
other people got here first.
Well, it is a pretty rad spot.
Maybe we should leave.
Ha, it's Norman. Hey, Norman Bates!
Oh, damn. It's Emma.
Hey, Emma. Gunner.
Looks like we all had the same idea.
We can find another spot.
That's stupid.
We can all hang out here.
I saw you at the beach
party. You sell pot, right?
- Maybe.
- Cool.
How cold do you think the water is today?
Want to find out?
Hey, Sheriff Romero, I
wanted to ask you something.
Yeah.
Can I call you by your name?
It's a little stupid at this point.
"Hey, Sheriff Romero."
I've never seen you in a suit.
Yeah, I'm on my way to testify
in the Kyle Miller hearing,
so... that's what you wanted to ask me?
Yeah, you can call me Alex.
No, actually, I'm gonna
talk to Mayor Woodriff
about giving me Lee Berman's seat.
I was wondering if you had
some tips on issues to cover.
You're not gonna get that seat.
What is it with you about me...
Just, I know what you're
up against, how things work.
It's very political, in the worst sense.
Well, my friend Christine
Heldens got me a meeting.
I don't think that could've happened
if there was no chance.
Well, good luck. I hope it goes well, I do.
Uh, listen.
It's a little awkward,
but I think you should be made aware of it.
What?
Well, sometimes at night,
when you have your light on in the bedroom,
you can see right through those curtains.
You can?
Yeah.
All right.
[Sighs] [Car door opens and closes]
Whoo-hoo!
Whoo! Not even cold!
- [Laughs]
- You're a total liar.
Whoo! [Laughter]
All right, who's next?
- Norman?
- I don't know.
Gunner looks kind of blue.
[Laughs] That's 'cause it's cold.
That's not a reason to not go and do it.
Come on. I'm gonna do it.
Yeah. Yeah, you just...
You just run and jump, huh?
Yeah, and don't forget to let go.
It's not brain surgery.
It looks kind of exciting.
[Laughs]
[Clears throat]
[Sighs]
Hoo!
Aah!
[Laughs] Aah!
Oh!
[Laughter]
Mother!
[Laughs]
Oh. Right to the bone.
- You're not cold?
- You kidding me?
Gonna have a frickin' heart attack.
Ah, I wish I could do it.
Can't you just take that
stuff out for a second?
Yeah, well, I do sometimes.
I don't think that's a good idea.
God, Norman, stop
worrying about everything.
She can totally do this.
I want to try.
You sure? It's really cold.
Yeah, I'm completely sure.
Guys, stop treating her
like she's made of glass.
Emma!
It will be fine. Okay.
Here I go!
[Screams and laughs]
[Laughs]
Emma?
Emma!
Get her tank.
It's okay.
Get her tank and some blankets!
[Gasping]
- Come on!
- [Coughing]
Let's go.
Now, breathe, okay? In and out.
All right, nice and easy.
Don't think about anything else.
[Crying]
What the hell do you think you were doing
- telling her to do that?
- I didn't know.
She could've died, and it
would've been your fault!
Everyone isn't just some
toy for you to play with!
Listen, man, she didn't know.
Shut up and stay out of this!
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
It's okay. I'm here.
Hey.
You ready to learn everything
you never wanted to know
about local politics?
Thank God, I actually got an appointment
with the mayor tomorrow.
I'm panicking. Come on in.
So nice of you to come
and help me with this.
Christine said that
you used to be a lawyer?
Yeah, for a while. Corporate law.
Why'd you stop?
Uh, well...
Okay, there's this old John Ford movie
called The Man Who Shot Liberty Valance,
and it's about this
young, idealistic lawyer
who goes to this wild
west town to civilize it.
Yeah, I know that movie. I love it.
So do I.
Anyway, I always identified
with that guy for some reason, the lawyer.
He was brave,
and he cared about people and justice,
so I went to law school.
And then?
And then my ex-wife found out
how much public defenders make a year,
and suddenly, I was at a white-shoe firm
doing mergers and acquisitions.
Trust me, you can only do that for so long
before you start sounding
like Scrooge Mcduck.
[Laughs]
Okay, should I just dive in?
- Yeah, sure.
- Okay.
My parents look like they should be
on the cover of an
album from the late '60s.
My dad started growing weed
for him and some of his buddies,
and turns out he kind
of had a knack for it.
It was awesome weed,
and everybody wanted it.
He was kind of a botanical artist.
And pretty soon, he had
this big business going.
Then, my parents both died
and left me the business,
whether I wanted it or not.
This is incredible.
Come on. Check it out.
How many strains you got going here?
[Laughs] At one time?
I don't know. Maybe 20, 30 varieties.
I blend them.
I crossbreed them.
It's the part I love.
Yeah, I can tell.
I need you to do something for me.
Oh, yeah? What's that?
I never should've given
my brother Gil's position.
He can't handle it.
Relax, this isn't a test.
I'm not gonna cut off your
head if you betray Zane.
That's good to know.
But here's what I need you to do for me.
I need you to watch him.
Make sure he doesn't do anything stupid.
Basically, I want you to run things
without letting him know
that you're running things.
It's not gonna be hard.
Speaking of running things,
if you're in charge,
how come I never see you?
I don't like getting my hands dirty.
That's kind of funny.
I mean, you really seem to like dirt.
I do like dirt.
It's honest.
And so my question would be two-pronged.
What are the city's goals with
regards to historic properties,
and what are the city's responsibilities?
- Norma.
- What? What'd I do wrong?
Nothing. But it's... it's not...
It's not about that.
You're fine,
and you've clearly done the research.
But that's not what's
gonna get you this seat.
Well, so what is?
Look.
You don't have to impress anyone
that you're competent or
informed or intelligent.
That's all very obvious.
But there's a... There's a depth
and a presence and a force about you
that's so engaging.
You've got to let that show.
Norma Bates is a lovely,
poised, competent woman,
who just happens to know
about municipal code
violations and overlay zones.
That's it.
Don't... don't be so worried
about bringing all this
information to the meeting,
that you leave yourself at home,
'cause you're the best part.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
[Whispers] Are you awake?
I am now.
Don't take this personally.
I won't.
Hello?
- Hey, Emma.
- Oh.
You... You feeling better today?
Fine. I-I shouldn't have done that.
I don't know what I was trying to prove.
Oh, yeah, I don't know what
any of us were trying to prove.
I just wanted to say thank you for...
Possibly saving my life.
Oh, no, I don't think I did.
I, um,
I lost it a bit.
You know, I hope I didn't embarrass you.
No, it was what it was.
It was a little scary,
and... and you just reacted.
Yeah.
Did I overreact?
Overreact?
You know, like, the
world's coming to an end.
You seemed upset.
You know, in a way that
a person would be upset
if someone they cared about might be hurt.
You're... You're just sensitive,
and to be honest, it
was nice to have someone
be that upset on my behalf.
Yeah, so it all just seemed normal.
You're asking the wrong person.
I don't really know what "normal" means.
But I don't want you to
worry about it, please.
You okay?
Oh, yeah. No, I'm... I'm fine.
I was just wondering how you were.
I'm glad you're better.
I am gonna get working on my crow.
Well, yeah, sure. I'll
let you get back to work.
I, um, just...
Just wanted to say thank you, Norman.
Yeah. You're welcome.
Yeah.
We'd like to preserve
the integrity of... wow.
We'd like to preserve the coastal integrity
of White Pine Bay.
We... we have to regulate
the construction density.
[Sighs] What? The construction d...
What time are you... what
time are you meeting the mayor?
2:00. Can I tell you my points again?
Mom, I've heard them many times.
- You know them.
- I know.
I know, and George told me not
to focus on the information.
- George did?
- Yeah.
He came by and helped me yesterday.
He's so nice.
What exactly did he tell you to focus on?
He told me that I shouldn't be so focused
on reciting facts that
I forget to bring myself,
that I'm the best part.
Yeah, George is right.
You should listen to George.
I got to go to the hardware store
and get glue for the glue gun.
Oh, and don't forget my
driver's test in the morning.
I'm not gonna forget.
When's the last time I
forgot an appointment for you?
- Norman?
- What?
Aren't you gonna wish me luck?
Getting this seat means everything to us.
Good luck, mother.
They'd be lucky to get you
on their stupid council.
The mayor is ready for you, Mrs. Bates.
I understand that coastal
development is necessary,
but it really needs to
be seriously controlled,
in order to maintain a
kind of quality of life
that I think we're all used to living here
in Pine White Bay... Or White Pine Bay.
So how do you know the Heldens?
Oh, Christine and I met
at community theater.
Ah. I love them both.
They're really great friends of mine,
and they love you.
That's nice to hear. Yeah.
They're great.
And you also know Nick Ford.
Yes, I do.
He also has really great
things to say about you,
and he really wants you to have this seat.
I appreciate his support.
Well, his support means something.
You really don't want to cross Nick Ford.
No, I don't suppose you do.
[Chuckles]
Okay, uh, great.
Thank you for stopping by.
Oh, you don't want me to
talk about my positions on...
Well, no, judging by the company you keep,
I know all that I need to know.
So it was nice to meet you, Norma.
- Nice to put a face to the name.
- Yeah.
You've made a really big impression
around here in a short time.
Well, that wasn't my intent.
I just wanted to move to a
nice, quiet town with my son.
Well, it's worked out for you.
You are in with all the right people.
- Okay, sure thing.
- So, uh...
Thanks again for stopping by.
I'll be making my decision very quickly.
Okay, very good. Thank you so much.
- You're welcome.
- Yep.
♪ And I've been lookin' at the stars ♪
♪ for a long, long time ♪
♪ I've been putting
out fires all my life ♪
♪ everybody wants a flame ♪
♪ they don't want to get burnt ♪
- Hey.
- Hi.
Sorry about the other day.
I'm like, "jump off a
rope and drown yourself."
Miss peer pressure here.
It's not your fault. I
totally wanted to do it.
Just got out of control.
Oh, Norman's not here right now.
I actually came to see you.
♪ Need that much, just some ♪
You know how Norman got
all crazy out of control?
Yeah.
Is he all right?
Well, he's sensitive and emotional.
Why? What happened?
What?
Please, tell me.
He's blacked out twice in front of me,
and he told me it's happened before.
Blacked out? You mean fainted?
- He fainted once at school.
- No, he, like, leaves his body.
He can physically move
and even talk a little,
but he's not in there.
And then he wakes up later.
It's like he's sleepwalking.
I had no idea.
Well, he told me not to tell his mom,
but now I'm worried I
should be telling someone,
'cause maybe there's
something really wrong with him
and he needs help.
He likes you a lot and trusts you.
I can see that.
So this is me, just kind of
giving you this information,
so you can do what you think is right.
There, I'm done.
Why didn't he want you to tell Norma?
He just said, "she'll get upset."
[Door closes]
Hello.
- Norma Bates?
- Yes.
Congratulations.
You're the newest member
of the city council.
Really?
I have a few items for you
to pick up today as well.
Oh, yeah, I can be there for that.
Your parking permit, keys, and...
Wait, you're sure about this, right?
The mayor is quite set on his decision.
Okay. Thank you very much for calling.
- Norman, guess what.
- What?
I got a seat. I'm on the council!
- Aw, yes!
- Yeah!
[Laughter] That's wonderful, mom.
[Sighs] You ready to go?
You got your DMV test in an hour.
Yeah, I'm ready.
Aw, I'm so proud of you, mother. Aw.
Yeah, you know, I didn't
think I could do it,
but I guess you just got
to believe in yourself,
- you know?
- Hmm.
And now, you're getting your license.
What a great day.
I told you moving here would
be the best thing we ever did.
[Laughs]
Don't forget your seat belt.
- Bates?
- Uh-huh.
Hello, there. Hi.
[Clears throat]
[Cell phone ringing]
Hi, Emma.
Hi. Are you coming back soon?
Uh, it's gonna be a few hours. Why?
I just have to tell you something.
What's wrong?
I'd rather tell you in person.
Well, now you got me all
worried, so just tell me.
Really, I'd rather...
Emma, what's wrong?
Did you know Norman is having blackouts?
What are... What are you talking about?
That girl, Cody Brennen, told me.
Told you what? How does she know anything?
She said that Norman has blacked out twice
when he's been with her,
like he's sleepwalking.
And he told her it had happened before.
I guess he told her not to
tell you, but she was worried.
She didn't know if she
should tell you anyways,
so she told me.
And I'm telling you.
I'm sorry.
Thanks, Emma. It's okay. Bye.
Can someone get their license
if they've been experiencing blackouts?
- Mother, what are you talking...
- Norman.
Has he experienced a loss of consciousness
in the last three years?
Yes, he has.
- [Scoffs]
- [Unbuckles seat belt]
I'm sorry,
but he absolutely can't get a license.
He can apply in three years,
if he has no recurrences.
[Car door closes]
[Soft music]
You have to talk to me eventually.
How could you do that to me?
How could I not? It's not safe.
Why, all of a sudden, do you even think
I'm having blackouts?
[Sighs] Norman, I just know.
Well, I want to know how you know,
because I don't believe you know.
I just think you're think
you're making all this up
because you don't want me to drive.
Cody Brennen told Emma.
She was worried about you.
Cody, huh?
Yeah, I warned you about her.
- Pull over.
- No, I'm not gonna pull over.
- I said pull over!
- [Tires screech]
[Car horn blares]
- Where are you going?
- Leave me alone, mother.
I don't want to. I'm worried.
Where are you going?
Go home, mother.
I'm not a little boy.
You can't keep me locked up in our house
for the rest of my life.
Since I can't drive, I'm walking.
Now, go home.
Okay, Norman. Okay.
[Pounding on door]
- Norman, what?
- Why did you tell Emma?
I was worried about you.
I didn't know what to do.
How could you do that to me?
- I trusted you!
- Shh. My dad's asleep.
He's been working all
night. You need to go.
I don't care.
I'm sorry, Norman, it seemed
like the right thing to do.
How could it be the right thing to do
when I specifically said
I didn't want to worry my mother?
I didn't tell your mom. I told Emma.
Well, that's as good as telling my mom.
I got to go work all night.
What the hell's going on out here, hmm?
Nothing, dad.
What's this guy doing here?
I don't need this right now, Cody.
I came here to talk to your daughter.
What?
Just go back to bed, dad. [Screams]
He goes, all right? Then I deal with you.
Let go of her! [Grunts]
Bringing your trashy, little
hookups back to my house?
It's not a hookup!
Leave her alone!
Dad!
[Ominous music]
Sync and corrections by madhatters
www.addic7ed.com